songselect.com 2019-04-11

# Privacy Policy — CCLI

## Your Privacy is Important to CCLI.

We’re committed to using the data that you share with us to provide the best possible service and experience. This Privacy Policy explains when and why we collect personal data, how we use it, and how we keep it secure.

When you provide us with personal data or use our websites, you agree to be bound by this policy which we may update from time to time.

### **Our Privacy Principles**

  * We will only collect personal data that is relevant to the services we provide, handle it securely and retain it only as long as necessary.
  * We will always ask you for your communication preferences and make it simple to change them.
  * We will not sell or give your information to a third-party organization other than our trusted service providers who provide certain secure business functions on our behalf
  * Our websites and online services only use temporary ‘session’ cookies to enhance your online experience. We do not use cookies to collect personally identifying information.

The information below provides more detail about how we use your data.

**Who We Are**  
**The Information We Collect**  
**How and Why We Use Personal Data**  
**How We Protect Your Personal Data**  
**Your Personal Data and Service Providers**  
**Your Personal  Data and Marketing**  
**How We Use Cookies**  
**Google Analytics**  
**Hotjar**  
**Comment Policy**  
**Update and Access Your Data: Your Rights and Control**

* * *

## Who We Are

CCLI is an international organization headquartered in Vancouver, Washington, USA, with offices around the world. As such, many of our systems and online services are employed globally.

We are strongly committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information and the security of our computer systems and online services.

Concerning the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information, CCLI makes every effort to ensure compliance with all applicable laws, including the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the all other local privacy regulations.

Back to top

* * *

## The Information We Collect

When you purchase licenses or services from CCLI, we will require only the personal information that is necessary for the administration of your account with us.

As a general rule, we do not collect personally-identifying information about you when you visit our websites or online services and we will retain only the information you choose to share with us.

When you sign up for CCLI’s licenses or services, you may provide some or all of the following:

  * Your title, name, email, postal address, and telephone numbers.
  * Usernames and passwords that you have chosen to log in to secure CCLI services such as Profile, Online Reporting, and SongSelect.

When you use our websites and online services we collect:

  * Information about the licenses and subscriptions that you purchase from us including your method of payment.
  * Information about the pages visited, and links clicked, including the date and time.
  * The internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site.
  * Information about the devices you have used, including mobile device identifiers, operating system, IP address and type of browser.

Our websites contain links to other websites. When you leave a CCLI website by linking to any of these sites, you are subject to the privacy policy of those sites.

When you interact with us through email, social media, surveys or promotions, we may collect:

  * Personal data that you freely provide about yourself that is relevant to the nature of the interaction, such as your name, username and email address.
  * Details of the emails you open, and links clicked.
  * Your comments in forums and feedback from surveys.

If you identify yourself by sending an e-mail containing personal information requesting that we mail information to you, we will use this information solely for responding to such requests and for our records. We may forward your e-mail to other CCLI employees who are better able to serve you.

### Data obtained from other sources

We may obtain personal data from other legitimate sources, including trusted third-party providers, and use this data to:

  * Verify and correct the information we hold.
  * Send information about licence renewal and account management.
  * Send marketing communications by post or email.
  * Initiate or deliver targeted content via online advertising and social media.

Back to top

* * *

## How And Why We Use Personal Data

CCLI will only collect and retain data that is required to administer your account or improve your experience; and we will provide you with information that we believe is important, in your interest to know, or that you have permitted us to send.

We use your data in the following ways:

To make our services available to you

  * Ensuring that the administration of your account is simple and secure.
  * Enabling us to provide the services you require and to process orders and refunds efficiently.
  * Enabling us to provide support and respond to inquiries quickly and accurately.
  * Where CCLI acts as an agent for other rightsholder organizations and you hold one of their licenses, we may be required to share your data with them.

To improve the way we operate and communicate

  * The data we hold about you enables us to improve our internal systems and our range of services.
  * By monitoring the use of our services, we can detect and prevent misuse and fraud and ensure that they can be accessed safely and securely.
  * We use web technologies such as cookies to improve the way our websites and online services work. Some cookies are necessary and, if disabled, will limit functionality and affect your user experience.
  * We use tools like Hotjar and Google Analytics to help us understand our users’ experience (e.g., how much time they spend on web pages, which links they choose, what they do and don’t like, etc.).
  * User feedback helps us build and maintain our services, determine technical design specifications and monitor system performance.

To ensure our communications are relevant and valuable

  * Interactions and browsing behavior help us understand you better and determine what is of most and least interest, meaning we can personalize our services, marketing communications, and promotions and measure their effectiveness.
  * We’re committed to respecting your marketing preferences and making it easy to change them.

### Consequences of Not Providing Your Data

You are not obligated to provide your personal information to Christian Copyright Licensing International, Inc. However, CCLI is unable to issue and administer copyright licenses, services and agreements without it.

Back to top

* * *

## How We Protect Your Personal Data

CCLI takes the protection of your data very seriously.

  * We use firewalls and data encryption to protect data that is stored electronically, and we take appropriate measures to ensure that our buildings and any files we store  physically are secure.
  * Whenever we collect or disclose personal data, we employ physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to ensure its safety. Consequently, we may ask you for proof of identity before we can disclose personal information to you.
  * We encrypt all data that is transferred electronically using the industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)
  * When your data is transferred, stored or processed in a different country, we employ appropriate measures to ensure that your data remains secure.

We cannot guarantee the security of any email provider or online service which is not managed by us, and which you use to transfer data to us.

Back to top

* * *

## Your Personal Data and Service Providers

CCLI works with reputable service providers who may process your data to perform business functions on our behalf. These include Hotjar, Google Analytics, MailChimp/Mandrill, SurveyGizmo, Scantech Group, and others.

All such service providers are contractually required to keep your data safe, use it only for the purposes agreed, and delete it when it is no longer required. They have agreed not share it, nor use it for their marketing purposes.

We will never give, sell or share your personal data with any third-party for any purpose other than that referred to above.

Back to top

* * *

## Your Personal Data and Marketing

CCLI would like to share potentially valuable or interesting information with you and, from time to time, ask for your feedback via online surveys.

  * When you provide us with your personal data, either by phone, email or a physical or online form, we will always provide a clear and simple way to confirm your communication preferences.
  * We will never assume your consent to receive email marketing. We will only send you marketing emails where you have opted-in to receive them.
  * We may give you the opportunity to opt-in to receive different marketing emails based on your interests. An opportunity to unsubscribe from any particular list will be clearly provided at the bottom of each email.
  * We may mail information to you that we believe will be of legitimate interest.
  * We will make it simple for you to change your communications preferences, which you can do at any time online, over the phone or by writing to us.

Back to top

* * *

## How We Use Cookies

A ‘cookie’ is a file placed on your personal computer’s hard drive by a website.

CCLI employs cookies to optimize its service to customers. We do not use cookies to collect  personally identifying information from users, nor to track user activities beyond our websites. CCLI does not maintain copies of cookies on our websites after you leave them.

Cookies store and exchange small pieces of temporary data between a website and a user’s computer which enable a “session” or “dialogue” between the two machines. With the session established, CCLI can tailor its responses (i.e., provide you with the information you want) and help you traverse our web pages efficiently and effectively.  A session is broken when you exit your browser.

CCLI uses “session cookies” — (i.e., temporarily stored cookies in your computer’s memory). Session cookies are normally deleted from a user’s computer when the user logs off the computer, or the user exits the browser.

For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our websites also employ systems to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

Unauthorised attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the law.

Back to top

* * *

## Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analytics service that uses cookies stored on your computer to collect and report website usage data.  We use Google Analytics to understand how visitors use our websites and to identify where we can improve our content and services.  Google collects the IP address you use when you visit the site but does not collect any other personal information about you.  We do not combine the information that Google collects with any other personally identifiable information.

Back to top

* * *

## Hotjar

We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) to understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience.

Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users’ needs and optimize our online services and experience (e.g., how much time they spend on web pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.). User feedback helps CCLI build and maintain quality service.

Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular the device’s IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile.

Neither Hotjar nor CCLI will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with data about an individual user. For further details, please see [Hotjar’s privacy policy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out of the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [Hotjar opt-out](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

Back to top

* * *

Comments on articles, blogs and videos can be helpful to other viewers, provided that a spirit of helpfulness is the intent of the person doing the commenting.

We review all comments on CCLI’s websites. We reserve the right to edit/delete spam comments, duplicate comments, unsupported accusations, vulgar comments, vile comments, personal attacks of any kind, terms offensive to groups when used in a derogatory manner, and any other comment deemed inappropriate at our discretion.

We reserve the right to ban offenders who post comments under another person’s name, submit an egregious comment or repeatedly submit comments that do not meet our standards.

Back to top

* * *

## Update and Access Your Data: Your Rights and Control

As a benefit of using CCLI’s services, we provide you with a way to access and update your information through CCLI Profile.  These features allow you to quickly update your personal information at any time, including your name, email address, and profile image.

We are committed to safeguarding your privacy and can only do so if you use CCLI Profile features as intended.  Some or all aspects of this Privacy Policy may not apply to individuals who share a login (email and password) with other members of an organization account.

If you believe the information that CCLI holds about you is incorrect and you are unable to correct it through our CCLI Profile service, please contact us, and we will update our records as soon as possible.

You have the right to see the personal data that we hold about you. However, how we deal with such requests, and whether we charge a fair administration fee may differ depending on the law in the country of your residence.

In all cases, if you would like a copy of the personal data we hold about you, please contact us using our [GDPR / Data Privacy contact form](https://us.ccli.com/contact-ccli/?department=data-privacy)

CCLI is committed to protecting your personal data and using it only in a manner that is appropriate, fair and transparent. If, however, you have a concern about our use of your data or wish to make a complaint,please contact us using our [GDPR / Data Privacy contact form](https://us.ccli.com/contact-ccli/?department=data-privacy). We will take all reasonable steps to resolve your query or complaint and to do so promptly.

Back to top

* * *

For further information about CCLI’s Privacy Policy, please contact us
